# Rodolphe Normandin

## Lifestyle Brand Management & Licensing - International Business Development - Open to opportunities

📞 +33 766294072 🔘 normandin.rodolphe@gmail.com 🛮 🔗 linkedin.com/in/rodolphenormandin 🔻 Paris, France

#### **SKILLS**



# New Business Development & Brand Licensing Proficiency

- Strategic thinking, identification of growth opportunities complementary to the core business, feasibility studies, search for funding, processes, and resources.
- Deployment of new businesses, strategic and commercial diversification projects, international expansion.
- Identification, negotiation, contracting, and deployment of partnerships, collaborations, and brand licensing agreements internationally.
- Diversification of distribution channels.
- · Sector expertise in lifestyle brands.



## Strategic, Operational and Digital Marketing Expertise

- Optimization and transformation of unique value proposition and product-service offerings.
- Creation and management of brands, platforms, product development, sourcing and manufacturing, planning, processes, and resources.
- Go-to-market strategy and launches.
- Budget and P&L ownership.
- Operational and digital marketing tools and tactics.

## CERTIFICATIONS

## Digital Strategy & Leadership Specialist™

Digital Marketing Institute, 2024

#### Certified Loyalty Marketing Professional™

The Loyalty Academy, 2023

### Qualified Licensing Practitioner™

Licensing International Trade Organisation, 2022

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master 2 Administration des Entreprises - French Exec. MBA

IAE Nantes / University of Nantes Business School

#### Bachelor of Arts Honours Economics

Middlesex University London

#### PROFILE HIGHLIGHTS

International experience, initially in marketing for B2C luxury and fashion brands, then in business development, partnerships, and brand licensing within B2B marketing agencies. Fluent in French and English. Available immediately for a new challenge and mobile internationally.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Founder • Lifestyle Brand Licensing & Partnerships

## **BLP CONSULTING - Self-employed**

**ii** 05/2022 - Present **♀** Paris

I facilitate market entry for European and American lifestyle brands, with a primary focus on Korea

- and Japan, supported by local business partners.

  Secured representation agreements with reproved properties: Penn Camelhak Maison Montagut
- Secured representation agreements with renowned properties: Penn, Camelbak, Maison Montagut, Barbara Bui, and ITV's Hell's Kitchen.

## **Licensing & Partnerships Director**

**TCC GLOBAL** 

**=** 2016 - 2022 **♀** Lond

London & Paris

- Led client relations at tcc global a loyalty marketing agency specialising in phygital rewards.
- Managed premium lifestyle and entertainment brands, including Alessi, Kartell, American Tourister, MasterChef, The Voice, and Red Bull Racing.
- Successfully expanded legacy partners and secured over 10 new ones, contributing to 50% of the Group's \$450 million turnover. Oversaw the development of the rewards' portfolio, marketing material and tactics utilised in loyalty campaigns globally.

## **VP Marketing Europe**

#### PF CONCEPT

Significantly enhanced customer engagement and regional brand visibility for licensed brand partners, including Balmain, Jamie Oliver, Slazenger through strategic B2B diversification strategies.

- Led digital marketing initiatives, overseeing SEO, CRM, and Marketing Automation for this agency specialised in product media solutions, licensed corporate gifts and loyalty rewards.
- Managed a team of 20 in curating and optimizing brands and the product portfolio.
- Achieved a +15% increase in turnover to €125 million and improved P&L profitability by +10%.

#### **Global Marketing Director**

## SAMSONITE

**=** 2006 - 2009

London

- Ownership of the product offering, product development, go-to-market strategies, global marcoms and P&L for the premium brand Samsonite Black Label. Coordinated multinational project teams and successfully launched 15 collections, distributed through 300+ doors, flagship boutiques, and the first dedicated e-store.
- Managed pioneering co-branded collaborations with Alexander McQueen, Viktor&Rolf and McLaren
- Led a tenfold increase in turnover to \$30 million, solidifying the brand's leadership in its segment.

## **Marketing & Sales Director**

## NATERE - Compagnie des Sacs & Accessoires

**=** 2004 - 2005

Paris

Paris

- Led the launch of Natère, a premium leather goods brand inspired by the craftsmanship heritage of
  the French atelier Compagnie des Sacs & Accessoires founded in 1894. Developed brand identity,
  oversaw product development, shaped and implemented the marketing and sales strategy.
- Successfully unveiled an inaugural collection and opened the first boutique.

## Senior Product Manager

**LANVIN** 

**=** 1996 - 2004

 Responsible for product offering, GTM launches, marketing tools, licensing partnerships, training, showroom sales, and performance of the product category Men's Leather Goods, Travel & Accessories

• Achieved a threefold increase in turnover to €6 million.

## Operational Marketing Manager

## YVES SAINT LAURENT PARFUMS

**iii** 1994 - 1995

♥ Tokyo

• Contributed to the launch of the Champagne / Yvresse fragrance in Japan